Feels
good. It feels good to talk about that,
man. It actually makes you feel good.
Makes you feel proud. All that. But
guess what happens? That alarm clock
goes off at 4:00 a.m. to train.
I don't want to be a seal today or I
don't want to be whatever today. I'll
start tomorrow. [music] And that's the
usual pattern of people's lives. Until
you really want to do something, you're
always going to be a talker. I know why
you hate me. You hate me because you're
probably in the bed right now. You're
probably an underachiever. You're
probably somebody who doesn't want to do
anything with your life. So, I make you
question everything about yourself. So,
I'm going to continue making you
question yourself by coming out here and
being even more successful. So, like I
said, I'm always examining myself every
day. What is it? What is it? Well,
there's only one thing you haven't
examined yet, and it's going back to the
beast, going back to the demon. So, when
I went back to him, I realized that that
was the unsolved mystery. At the end of
the day, I asked myself one question.
Can I take one more step? And usually
the answer is yes. So, if you can answer
that question and not take another step,
that is real failure. That is real
quitting. So, a lot of people can take
one more step, but they choose not to. I
don't know if you can take two steps.
You got to answer that question after
you take the first step.
But I can always take one more step. So
if I choose not to, that's on me. And I
got to live with that. But all the times
that I was like, this is I I'm not going
back. And I went back. I'm not going
back. And I went back. It showed me even
more of what we have as as as humans if
we're willing to go there and we're
willing to push that extra step. So for
me, this was the new level. Let's not
quit yet, God. Because let's [__] think
about your options.
Where are you going to end up if you
quit this? Where are you going to go?
What's amazing about the human mind is
that it becomes your new norm?
Like to to to think that I can run 200
miles, 240 miles, and that becomes like
running 50. I never thought that was
possible. This is why I'm I'm always
pushing that limit because I know that
within pushing these limits, there's
always more. But what it did was it
showed me what is possible. And that's
what set a new stage for me. That's when
I realized, oh man, I've really been
underachieving my entire life. But it
taught me when it's possible. Because we
all think about quitting, which is hard.
It's hard to process information during
pain
because that pain takes over and you
can't think rationally.
You're thinking about fight or flight.
Save yourself. That's not a rational
thought. It's not a thought that's going
to get you through
hard times. But there's a lot of thought
behind a person being a born loser
becoming who I am today. You don't just
wake up and just rocky.
You got to wake up and think about, you
know, there's a process to getting
better. And that process is never
finished. And then once you do this over
and over and over again, it becomes like
breathing. I don't want to live this
lifestyle, but to get to the other side
of this, I have to. So, if you really
want it, you realize what trying is and
what [music] trying is not. Your brain
is the most powerful weapon in the
world. Once you put away your phones and
your computers and all that we have
nowadays, that's great. We're up to
date. We you know you But your brain is
the only thing you have when you're
going through depression, when you when
you're [music] going through hard times,
when you're going through death, real
life. You can't Google that, man.
[music] There's 24 hours in the day
where you're alone in this brain and
your brain is talking to you in all kind
of ways and it wants to control you and
pull you in these different pockets. If
you can't control your own brain and
[music] your brain controls you, you're
got to tell your brain where you want to
go and how you want to go and how you
want to get there. You got to control
it. If not, it's over. That's how you
have to live your life. When that alarm
clock goes off at 4:00 or 5 in the
morning, your mind says, "No, you and
all I knew back then was hard work." The
only way anything gets accomplished.
[music] You got to work hard. You got to
work hard. I can't get this paragraph. I
can't remember what the in this
paragraph to pass this test to [music]
get in the military. Read again. Still
not getting it? Read again. But if
you're not getting it, write it out. And
that's how I started learning. Okay.
Well, I can't. I [music] got to write
out every thing I do and then write it
out again and write it out again. And
guess what happened? I got it. [music] I
can't swim. I'm negative buoyant. Go
back again. I can't swim. Go back again.
Go back again. Go back again. I got it.
I realize if I keep going back and going
back and going back until it just
becomes your mind will say, "Okay, we're
going to figure it out. It'll find a way
>> because he is not going to stop. It's
not like I'm going to try one more time.
No, I'm It's just like alarm clock goes
off. Boop. We're going back. I can't
read, right? [music] We're going back. I
gave myself no way out. And my mind
realized that. They said, "Okay, we're
going to adapt and overcome." Now, that
was my mindset. And that's how you get
through things. You put yourself, you
immerse yourself in wherever it is. You
become that. you become that and give
yourself no way out and but people don't
want to go through the process of focus
of teaching yourself how to truly focus.
I am literally I was the lowest form on
earth no talent no ability to learn and
I literally know what it is to be rock
bottom and to build that up. It's like
whether you believe in God or not I do.
He put this lab rat, which is me, on
this planet and said, "Let me
like running is running. It sucks, but
you have a choice to make. Do you want
to sit down and go back to that guy you
once were?" No. So, this is what it
takes.
>> It seems like, especially with
confidence, right, or self-esteem,
there's a relationship between
confidence and competence.
>> So, what you're looking to do is try and
have what you believe that you can do be
ahead of what you can do. Now, you're
not looking for it to be delusional. You
don't want it to to be able to believe
that you can do something like fly,
right? But you need to have a
relationship between the two. But what
people are asking for is for their
confidence to be so far ahead of their
competence that or without having even
been competent at anything in the
beginning. And that's just delusion.
That's fantasy. Build belief. Belief is
like there's an afterchool special
belief where the mom says, "Believe in
yourself." And that's all great, but
there's also a built belief. Like for
me, I came from a bad place. How I build
belief is through the the daunting tasks
I put myself through. So that's proof
positive that I can. So it correlates.
And that's how this piece of kid I once
thought I was built belief by saying,
"hm, I was in three hell weeks. I went
to Ranger School. I tried out for Delta
Selection."
>> Undeniable stack of proof. That is proof
mother. So whenever you think whenever
you think you can't confidence comes
from the thing that [music] you built.
You must build belief. You must build
confidence. It can't be like hey um I'm
going to go knock that out. You got to
look over here and say I can knock that
out. It's a belief and it's built on
what you put in to yourself. It starts
with yourself man. You got to start
diving into those things that you are
afraid of. You don't gain confidence by
going to the spot that makes you feel
good. It's could be a false reality. And
the second life gives you that
challenge. All you want to do is go back
to what made you confidence or or or or
what gave you confidence is that happy
spot. No. What gave me confidence was
spending years [music] at a kitchen
table trying to learn how to read and
write on my own. Realizing I can't learn
the way you learn.
>> I can't. But I can learn. What gives you
confidence? Not being afraid.
It's overcoming the fear. That's what
gives me confidence is facing these
things. Overcoming them. And maybe not
overcoming them every day, but facing
them and facing them and facing pretty
soon like this. You know what, man? This
is where it's at.
>> It's not in that comfort zone. It's in
the discomfort zone is where my
confidence is getting built. That's
where it's getting built. But people
want to and they want an easier answer.
>> Yeah.
>> There has to be an easier way. There's
not. I'm sorry. I searched for it my
entire life. [laughter]
>> You did. You lied.
>> I lied. I did everything. And I still
felt empty. You never examined this.
happiness, peace, enlightenment, it's
all up here, man. It's all up here. It's
all up here. You just got to be willing
to go and face it. And that's the hard
part. Where most people quit,
I had just started.
And when you take that mindset and you
learn to flip that around, that's what
made me powerful
and my body followed. failure, hell,
[music] disappointment, discomfort
is a great learning tool. And many
people don't understand that it's these
few moments in life that you have. Like
for me, I always talk about it. Rocky
won round 14. That one 2 minute and 13
[music] second clip of Rocky getting up
when Apollo knocked him down. that one
clip when I was going through a very bad
time in my life, I saw what I wanted to
be. And it wasn't a guy that won. It
wasn't a guy that won everything he did.
It was a guy that kept getting up after
being knocked down. So, I realized if
that 2 minutes [music] and 13 seconds
changed my life. So, I was I saw
something that I needed to be in the
world I was living in.
Maybe my story
will give [music] someone the 2 minutes
and 13 seconds they need to change their
life. Everybody's got a story. We don't
share it on social media. We share our
nice life on social media. We have We
all have a dungeon. I'm just willing to
talk about mine. I don't care how you
perceive David God is because through my
journey I figured out the one piece I
was missing. I thought it was cars. I
thought it was women. I thought it was I
thought it was money. I thought it was
everything. The one piece I was missing
was me having the courage to face
myself. Where I got my work ethic from
was the hours I had to spend learning
this.
When you sit down and you're not smart
and you have a disability
and you still want to be in the top of
your class, I didn't want to just get
by. When I realized that I can learn
through hard work and I can beat the val
Victorian in school, but I got put in 10
hours more a day than he does. You know
what kind of strength comes from that?
When you're sitting down and that guy
that that valictorian study for an hour
and you know I caught you. I caught you
and I am dumb but I have the work ethic
to catch you. That's where David Gaga
got really invented was at a kitchen
table with 20 spiral notebooks that were
empty and then 3 months later
>> they were full. And when you can go
through that I still have them in my
storage unit. You go through these
spiral notebooks of your life and you
realize this is how I learned. This is
unbelievable.
>> Why is the truth so important? [music]
You have to have the truth to have a
starting point. And your true self is
found honestly in that very
uncomfortable zone. We all look for
toughness. We all want it. But we look
for it in a comfortable environment. You
will not find toughness in a comfortable
environment. Those of you who are
listening to this, whoever hear this,
you will not find it. I was trying to
look for it everywhere. The only way you
find it is to drown yourself in a
position where you're just out of sorts.
[music]
But you say, you know what, man?
That once you come face to face with who
you are, you have a starting point. I
was born David Gogggins. David Gogggins
wasn't good enough. He was a scared,
bullied, abused kid who struggled in
life. And that kid, whenever something
got tough, no matter how hard I trained,
no matter how ready I was, whenever
something got tough for me, David
Gogggins, the real David Gogggins, would
come out and he would quit. So I
realized this over a period of time. So
I had to build Gogggins. And in that
process, that's where I get better. You
have to be your best self and your least
motivated. And that's the tricky part
about all that. Motivation is [music]
just a word. You have to have these
different things in your mind on where
you want to go and know that motivation
is not going to get me there because I'm
not going to always be motivated.
>> Joo said the exact same thing. He said
that discipline eats motivation for
breakfast.
>> And discipline is good too, but without
a clear headsp space there's no
discipline.
>> What do you mean?
>> So let's say we have a circuit breaker.
Okay. And I'm loading everything up to
one circuit. Just load it up. It's going
to blow. And once that thing blows, man,
the circuit's all up. You got to have
each thing plugged into the right spot
like a crowded garage. You can't put
anything in it. Once your brain is
crowded, discipline is great. Motivation
is great. But if you can't fit in your
brain because it's all cluttered with
there's no discipline. So a lot of
people talk about discipline. Okay,
great. Why do you fall off the wagon?
Why can't I continue with this routine?
Going to the gym, being better, waking
up early, eating the right foods. It's
because maybe it's your kids, maybe it's
your wife, maybe it's your job, and it's
all just stuffed in your brain. You
don't have it compartmentalized and
organized in these nice shelves. So,
where am I going to put discipline in
that mind if I can't find other? You got
to be able to find all these different
things in your mind. Oh, I can put
discipline right there. I can put
consistency right there. I can put all
these things right there in that spot.
If your life is not organized
and your life being everything around
you because it takes one little up piece
of outside interference to clutter your
whole mind. That was the biggest thing.
I had to stop caring what people thought
about me. I realized that everybody's
up. That's the one thing I realized.
[music] I walked around and I put these
people on a on a pedestal. Everybody was
better than me. So, I can't tell you
anything about me because you're going
to judge me and I'm gonna feel even
worse than what I am. What I realized
once I calmed my mind down and sat back
and looked at how jacked up this world
is. Once you realize that you are not
alone, everybody that's talking to you
about how jacked up you are, only thing
they've done better than you is they've
hidden their world better than you have.
That's all they've done. Most of us fail
in life because we're afraid of what
everyone around you is thinking.
>> That's 100% truth. So, we live by the
narrative of other people. When I first
called a recruiter to be a Navy Seal and
I was 297 pounds, the first recruiter
looked at me and said, "You're not going
to be able to make this, man." So, what
he was doing was he was projecting his
energy on me. He knew he couldn't be
Navy Seal. So, God helped this black guy
cuz I was only the 36th African-American
to make it through in over 70 years.
How's this black [music] fat guy going
to make it through in my He wasn't even
willing to try. So, he's projecting it.
So a lot of us who are negative people
all we do is project how we feel on
other people. So what happens is there's
a lot of negative people walking around
the planet earth who are afraid to try
cuz everybody a lot of people are very
negative in this world. So we are afraid
to fail. Why told you man tried it dude
just chill out relax. Why you so crazy?
[music] Why you so obsessed? So all that
stuff drives the the uh quitting mind I
call it. The mind wants to quit. The
mind's tired. The mind's tired. The mind
is deserving. The mind thinks it's very
deserving. So yes, the the the [music]
biggest problem in this world is other
people, not yourself. It's other people
in your head. They are puppet mastering
you pretty much on your life.